<vertical>
    <mentoring>
        <html>
            <h3>Worry box</h3>
            <p>Here are your "Doing / Not Doing Insteads."</p>
        </html>

        <answer name="doing-not-doing-instead" read_only="true" />

        <html>
            <p>Now, let's fill out the "worry box." If you were to consider doing the opposite of each of those behaviors in Column 2, what are the fears, worries, feelings of loss that come up for you?</p>

            <blockquote>
                <p>Let's return to Fred, our aspiring novelist whose goal is to "get better at integrating creative writing into my daily life" but instead admits that he surfs the internet instead of writing and doesn't schedule writing time into his week.</p>
                <p>Fred thinks about how it would feel to give himself a set schedule for writing and hold himself to it. He tries to imagine what it would be like to have and keep a schedule. Why is that such a turn-off?  What feeling of dread arises?  Fred thinks for a moment and realizes that he only wants to write when inspiration strikes. He loves writing when he has a creative impulse and lots of energy to pursue his ideas. Writing on a schedule seems boring and routine. It sounds like the opposite of creativity and inspiration. He makes the following entry in his worry box:</p>
                <p>Worry Box: If I were to maintain a writing schedule, I'm afraid of feeling stifled, dull, like I am plodding along.</p>
            </blockquote>
        </html>

        <quizz name="list-common-worries" type="choices">
            <question>You can enter your worries below, or you can view some common worries first. Would you like to see a list of some of the most common fears and worries people list?</question>
            <choice value="yes">Yes</choice>
            <choice value="no">No</choice>

            <tip display="yes">
                <html>
                    <p>If I were to do the opposite of one of my column 2 doing/not doing instead behaviors&#x2026;</p>
                    <ul>
                        <li>I am afraid of looking stupid / being rejected</li>
                        <li>I am afraid of being vulnerable, open to rejection</li>
                        <li>I am afraid of letting others down</li>
                        <li>I am afraid of looking weak and ineffective</li>
                        <li>I am afraid of looking selfish</li>
                        <li>I am afraid of being seen as controlling or a micro-manager</li>
                        <li>I am afraid of failing, being a loser</li>
                        <li>I am afraid of looking bad</li>
                        <li>I am afraid of feeling vulnerable</li>
                        <li>I am afraid of being alone</li>
                        <li>I am afraid of showing what I care about, what I can do</li>
                        <li>I am afraid people won't like me</li>
                        <li>I am afraid of looking like I think I am superior</li>
                        <li>I am afraid something will go wrong and it will be my fault</li>
                    </ul>
                </html>
            </tip>

            <tip display="no">You can read this later by changing your answer to Yes.</tip>
        </quizz>

        <html>
            <p>Enter your worries here. Make sure you consider doing the opposite of each of the behaviors you listed in the "Doing / Not Doing Instead."</p>
        </html>

        <answer name="worry-box" />
    </mentoring>
</vertical>
