<vertical>
    <mentoring>
        <html>
            <h3>Hidden Commitments</h3>
            <p>We hold Hidden Commitments to prevent the fears or losses in our worry box from happening. In many cases, these Hidden Commitments keep us from even feeling the fears or losses. They protect us from those bad feelings and bad results.</p>
            <p>Many times, you can simply change the wording in your worry box, converting your list of fears and worries into a list of Hidden Commitments.</p>

            <blockquote>
                <p>That is what Fred did. As you'll recall, Fred wants to get better at integrating creative writing into his daily life but instead admits that he surfs the internet instead of writing and doesn't schedule writing time into his week. If he were to schedule writing time, he worries he would feel like his creativity is being stifled. He converts this worry into the language of a commitment.</p>
                <p>Worry:  I'm afraid of feeling stifled, dull, like I am plodding along.</p>
                <p>Hidden Commitment: I am committed to never feeling stifled or under force.</p>
            </blockquote>

            <p>Ideally, you want these commitments to capture as much of the danger/worry/dread from which you have been protecting yourself as you can. In some cases, you may look to see if it makes sense to change the wording a little bit when you convert your fears and worries to commitments. Or, you may add entries that really express the ways you have been keeping yourself out of that territory. Fred could try different ways of wording his commitment to get to what is most fearsome and dangerous for him.</p>

            <blockquote>
                <p>Other possible Hidden Commitments for Fred:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>I am committed to experiencing myself only as brilliant, inspired, listening only to the beautiful voice of my muse.</li>
                    <li>I am committed to not finding out whether I have the discipline and drive to be a writer and not just a dabbler.</li>
                    <li>I am committed to preventing myself from finding out that I don't actually have anything meaningful to say in my writing.</li>
                </ul>
            </blockquote>
        </html>

        <quizz name="display-common-hidden-commitments" type="yes-no">
            <question>You can enter your Hidden Commitments below, or you can view some common commitments first. Would you like to see a list of some of the most common Hidden Commitments?</question>

            <tip display="yes">
                <html>
                    <ul>
                        <li>I am committed to not looking stupid / being rejected</li>
                        <li>I am committed to not being vulnerable, open to rejection</li>
                        <li>I am committed to never letting others down</li>
                        <li>I am committed to always making others happy</li>
                        <li>I am committed to not looking weak and ineffective</li>
                        <li>I am committed to not looking selfish</li>
                        <li>I am committed to not being seen as controlling or a micro-manager</li>
                        <li>I am committed to not being a loser</li>
                        <li>I am committed to always looking good</li>
                        <li>I am committed to not being vulnerable</li>
                        <li>I am committed to not being alone</li>
                        <li>I am committed to hiding what I care about, what I can do</li>
                        <li>I am committed to having everyone like me</li>
                        <li>I am committed to hiding my feelings of being superior</li>
                        <li>I am committed to not being responsible for anything going wrong</li>
                    </ul>
                </html>
            </tip>

            <tip display="no">You can read this later by changing your answer to Yes.</tip>
        </quizz>

        <answer name="hidden-commitments" />
    </mentoring>
</vertical>
