<vertical>
    <mentoring>
        <html>
            <h3>Checking your Hidden Commitments</h3>
            <p>Now, let's make sure your Hidden Commitments meet the criteria for appropriate entries. Here is what you wrote:</p>
        </html>

        <answer name="hidden-commitments" read_only="true" />

        <quizz name="hidden-commitments-fear" type="choices">
            <question>Do all of your Hidden Commitments follow from fear?</question>
            <choice value="yes">Yes</choice>
            <choice value="maybenot">Maybe not</choice>
            <choice value="understand">I don't understand</choice>

            <tip reject="maybenot">The third column helps us understand why we persist in doing our "doings instead."  Immunity to Change suggests that there might very good reasons why we are doing those things, but we usually are not aware of what those reasons are. If some of our reasons for our "doings instead" are scary to us, it is probably harder to identify them, reflect on them, and consider what we might learn from them. Our Hidden Commitments are our mental strategies for standing far away from what we see as danger, disaster, or vulnerability. They are commitments to protecting-usually over-protecting ourselves from these terrible feelings and outcomes. These forms of protection therefore often look quite undesirable to us &#x2014; showing us ways we can look and feel selfish, weak, overly controlling, at the mercy of others, insecure or needy, vain or egomaniacal. They take us into territory within ourselves we usually want to avoid. The yuckier your Hidden Commitments feel to you, the more you can be sure you have identified a powerful and perhaps up-until-now secret force that has been directing your behavior against your conscious will. If your third column commitments don't include what felt most powerfully dangerous from your fears, these commitments will not lead to the most powerful learning for you. If your entries don't capture your fears and worries, spend some time thinking, "What is the danger lurking for me?  In what way am I trying to protect myself?"  Then go back and revise your entries by TODO-LINK.</tip>
            <tip reject="understand">What we mean when we say that Hidden Commitments should follow from the fear is that they should include the fear somehow. They are commitments to prevent this fear from happening, so you should still be able to see the fear in them. An easy way to do this is to create a Hidden Commitment is to change the wording of your fear. For example, the fear "I worry that people will think I'm stupid" can easily be changed to the Hidden Commitment, "I am committed to not looking stupid."</tip>
        </quizz>

        <quizz name="hidden-commitments-noble" type="choice">
            <question>Do any of your Hidden Commitments sound "noble"?</question>
            <choice value="maybe">Maybe</choice>
            <choice value="no">No</choice>
            <choice value="understand">I don't understand</choice>

            <tip reject="maybe">It's easy to misunderstand what we mean by commitment. The word commitment sounds like something you should feel proud of and something you should deliberately choose as a goal. But the Hidden Commitments in your third column should feel very different. If your third column entries are powerful, these commitments will actually make you feel very uncomfortable. Often people tell us they feel a sinking or tightening sensation in their chest or gut. While all of these experiences are indeed unpleasant, we think that is actually a positive sign that you are coming to see something powerful about yourself. Our Hidden Commitments are our mental strategies for standing far away from what we see as danger, disaster, or vulnerability. They are commitments to protecting &#x2014; usually over-protecting ourselves from these terrible feelings and outcomes. These forms of protection therefore often look quite undesirable to us &#x2014; showing us ways we can look and feel selfish, weak, overly controlling, at the mercy of others, insecure or needy, vain or egomaniacal. They take us into territory within ourselves we usually want to avoid. The yuckier your Hidden Commitments feel to you, the more you can be sure you have identified a powerful and perhaps up-until-now secret force that has been directing your behavior against your conscious will. If any of your Hidden Commitments sound noble &#x2014; if they sound like things you would be proud to say out loud &#x2014; spend some time thinking, "What is the danger lurking for me?  In what way am I trying to protect myself?"  Then go back and revise your entries by TODO-LINK.</tip>
            <tip reject="understand">Noble commitments are values that we are proud of, that we like, that we are happy to hold and happy for others to see. Hidden commitments should not be noble. Instead, they should feel yucky, unpleasant. Maybe we even feel a little sick when we see them. For example, "I am committed to being successful" sounds pretty noble, pretty great, something I am happy to be working on and happy for others to know about me. So that is not a good Hidden Commitment. But, maybe there is a yucky, unpleasant version of this that could be a good Hidden Commitment. If my fear is "that I won't succeed," I can explore that fear a bit further. What would be the worst thing about not succeeding for me?  Maybe I would really hate for others to see me making mistakes. (Hidden commitment:  I am committed to not making any mistakes in front of others.)  Maybe the worst thing would be that I would prove to myself that I am not special or gifted. (Hidden commitment:  I am committed to believing I am special or gifted.)  Maybe the worst thing is that I will be wrong. (Hidden commitment:  I am committed to being right. Or, I am committed to not being wrong.)  These Hidden Commitments are not so noble. I feel a little ashamed and vulnerable. I feel like I want to keep them hidden.</tip>
        </quizz>

        <quizz name="hidden-commitments-protection" type="choices">
            <question>Do all of your Hidden Commitments reflect a commitment to self-protection?</question>
            <choice value="yes">Yes</choice>
            <choice value="maybenot">Maybe not</choice>
            <choice value="understand">I don't understand</choice>

            <tip reject="maybenot">Hidden commitments are forms of self-protection. They protect us from the dangers that lurk in our fears. Our Hidden Commitments are our mental strategies for standing far away from what we see as danger, disaster, or vulnerability. They are commitments to protecting &#x2014; usually over-protecting ourselves from these terrible feelings and outcomes. These forms of protection therefore often look quite undesirable to us &#x2014; showing us ways we can look and feel selfish, weak, overly controlling, at the mercy of others, insecure or needy, vain or egomaniacal. They take us into territory within ourselves we usually want to avoid. When you look at your Hidden Commitments, you should also be able to see how you have been protecting yourself from that dangerous territory. If yours don't, spend some time thinking, "What is the danger lurking for me?  In what way am I trying to protect myself?"  Then go back and revise TODO-LINK</tip>
            <tip reject="understand">Hidden commitments are a form of self-protection. We have them to keep us away from danger and fear. They protect us when they prevent us from changing our behavior. They protect us from what we fear would happen if we change our behavior. They tell us we must never do the opposite of what we wrote in column 2 or the terrible fears and worries we have in column 3 might happen. For example, maybe I am trying to get better at being honest with my friends (column 1), but I only tell them what I think they want me to say (column 2). If I were to tell them what I really think (the opposite of column 2), I fear they won't like me. I have a Hidden Commitment to having everyone like me. That commitment keeps me from telling my friends what I really think and so it protects me from my friends not liking me. It even protects me from worrying that my friends won't like me. Unfortunately, it also keeps me from making progress on my Improvement Goal of being honest with my friends.</tip>
        </quizz>

        <quizz name="hidden-commitments-doing-not-doing" type="choices">
            <question>Do all of your Hidden Commitments show why each of your column 2 behaviors (Doing / Not Doing Insteads) makes good sense?</question>
            <choice value="yes">Yes</choice>
            <choice value="maybenot">Maybe not</choice>
            <choice value="understand">I don't understand</choice>

            <tip reject="maybenot">Your Hidden Commitments should show you that the behaviors in column 2 that look bad (because they undermine your column one goal) are actually useful behaviors from the point-of-view of the psychic immune system. They are useful because they help you uphold your column 3 commitments, which are powerful Hidden Commitments. You should be able to see why it hasn't worked in the past and won't work in the future to try to change those behaviors only through willpower or increased effort. The harder you step on the gas (trying to make progress on your column 1 goal by changing your column 2 behaviors), the harder your other foot will step on the brakes (upholding your column 3 commitment by maintaining your column 2 behaviors). As a result, we spend a great deal energy trying to go in opposite directions at the same time. If you can't see how your Hidden Commitments make your behaviors in column 2 look perfectly reasonable, that's a sign that you've gotten off track somewhere. Look to see if you need to revise your Hidden Commitments or go back to your fears TODO-LINK to see if you need to get clearer about them.</tip>
            <tip reject="understand">Your column 2 behaviors (the doing/not doing insteads) are bad because they work against your column 1 goal (your Improvement Goal). But we can also see that are good too because they uphold your column 3 commitments (Hidden Commitments). Our Improvement Goal pulls us in one direction, and our Hidden Commitments pull us in the opposite direction. In fact, we are working very hard to move in both directions at the same time, and so we actually don't move at all. That is how our immune system works.</tip>
        </quizz>

        <message type="completed">
            Great! You have indicated that your Hidden Commitments follow from fear, reflect a commitment to self-protection, are not noble, and reveal why their matching column 2 behavior makes good sense.
        </message>
    </mentoring>
</vertical>
