<vertical>
    <mentoring>
        <html>
            <h3>Big assumptions</h3>
            <p>There are two options you can follow here to create your Big Assumptions.</p>
            <p>Option 1) Use deduction. Look at one of your Hidden Commitments. Now ask yourself, "what assumptions must I be making that make this commitment necessary for me?" "What could be the assumptions I hold that sustain this commitment?"  For example, if I am committed to always being right, what might I be assuming?  Maybe&#x2026;</p>
            <ul>
                <li>I assume that if I am not right, I can't feel good about myself.</li>
                <li>I assume that if I am not right, others won't trust me.</li>
                <li>I assume that if I am not right, no one will like me.</li>
                <li>I assume I am either right or wrong.</li>
                <li>I assume I should never say or do something that might turn out to be wrong.</li>
                <li>I assume that if I am always right, I will always feel good about myself.</li>
                <li>Only you know which Big Assumption is true for you.</li>
            </ul>
            <p>Sometimes worry box entries (rather than Hidden Commitments) reveal assumptions.</p>

            <blockquote>
                <p>Here is Fred's worry box entry: "If I were to schedule writing time, I'm afraid I would feel like my creativity is being stifled." This assumption underlies that fear: If I were to schedule writing time, I assume that I would feel like my creativity is being stifled. That is an assumption Fred is making. Fred may feel that assumption is 100% true. Or he may know it is not 100% true, but also admit that he acts as if it is. Or he may be unsure about whether it is true or not.</p>
                <p>Option 2) Use the formula. Choose a 3rd column commitment and consider its inverse (e.g. "I am committed to never revealing that I don't have all the answers." The inverse is "I do reveal I don't have all the answers.") Now construct a sentence, the first half of which is in this form: I assume that if [inverse of 3rd column entry] THEN: the second half of the sentence will be your honest completion of the sentence. e.g. I assume that if I do reveal I don't have all the answers&#x2026; then I will be considered a fraud.</p>
                <p>Let's work with Fred's Hidden Commitment: "I am committed to never feeling stifled or under force." The inverse if "I do feel stifled or forced." His formula is: "I assume that if I do feel stifled or forced, then I will feel absolutely awful, my creative spark will be extinguished, and it might be permanent."</p>
            </blockquote>

            <p>Please review your map so far, especially your Hidden Commitments, before entering your Big Assumptions.</p>
        </html>

        <mentoring-table name="TODO-MAP" />

        <html>
            <p>Enter your Big Assumptions here.</p>
        </html>

        <answer name="big-assumptions" />
    </mentoring>
</vertical>
