<vertical>
    <mentoring>
        <html>
            <h3>Help on Revising Immunity to Change Maps</h3>
            <p>Now, let's make sure your goal meets the criteria for a strong column 1. Here is your goal:</p>

            <h4>Making Your Map More Powerful</h4>
            <p>If you have filled in columns 1-3 (or even 4) but haven't yet created an immunity map that feels both compelling and intriguing to you, it is worth going back over your answers now to see if you can revise them. Even if your map feels like it packs a punch, you may feel like you need to tinker with it a bit more. In this section, we explain some techniques that certified Immunity to Change coaches use with their coaching clients, in hopes that they will support you in creating a stronger map. Before coaches work with clients on overturning their immunities, we always spend at least one session on their immunity map to make sure that it is in great shape!  Here are our suggestions for how you can do that for yourself.</p>

            <h4>Suggestions for Column 1: Your Starting Commitment</h4>
        </html>

        <quizz name="improvement-goal-right" type="yes-maybenot-understand">
            <question>Do you think you have the right Improvement Goal?</question>
            <tip reject="maybenot">Check to see how compelling your column one goal still feels for you. For some people, it takes time to get the first column right. A common mistake people make is choosing a goal that does not implicate them. See if that's the issue for you. Are you clearly naming what you need to get better at? If so, then ask yourself whether the goal you've named feels very important to you. It may have felt that way when you started your map, but sometimes the importance fades relative to seeing a Hidden Commitment; or its importance may simply fade over time. If it doesn't feel really worthwhile to you, it's worth starting a new map. One way to jump-start identifying a powerful enough new focus is to explore whether there is a goal you have pursued unsuccessfully in the past that continues to be important to you (perhaps you've outright failed, or you've made minimal progress or backslid). If you choose to identify a more promising goal, you'll do best to go to topic 6. TODO-LINK</tip>
            <tip reject="understand">Now that you have tried to create an immunity map, do you want to choose a different Improvement Goal?  Maybe you have changed your mind and want to focus on something else?  Maybe you want your goal to be more specific?  Maybe your goal feels too specific?  Maybe now that you have done a lot of thinking, you realize that you want to change your column 1 commitment?  That's fine. You can go to TODO-LINK</tip>
        </quizz>

        <quizz name="improvement-goal-wording" type="yes-maybenot-understand">
            <question>Do you think you have the right wording for your Improvement Goal?</question>
            <tip reject="maybenot">
                <html>
                    <p>Does your column 1 Improvement Goal accurately express your hopes?  Some people find that they need to play around with the ways they describe their commitment until it says exactly what they mean. We have also found that some clients are helped by really focusing on the get better at part of their commitment. Such clients should get more specific about what most needs to change if they are to achieve their goal. For example, "I am committed to being more compassionate" might get revised to "I am committed to getting better at listening openly and carefully when to my spouse."</p>
                    <p>Or you might find that making your commitment more general leads to more powerful learning. For example,  "I am committed to losing 35 pounds so that I can wear a size 10 dress" might get revised to "I am committed to being more deliberate about what I eat, when I eat, and how much I eat."    When you have settled on the wording that feels best to you, continue on to see if those revisions in Column 1 help you revise the other columns as well.</p>
                </html>
            </tip>
            <tip reject="understand">Are there other ways to say your Improvement Goal that might be better for you?  Are the words you are choosing the best ones to use?  If you try to use different words, your goal may feel more accurate or more powerful. Or, you can try to change the focus a little bit to see if that makes an important difference.</tip>
        </quizz>

        <html>
            <h4>Suggestions for Column 2: The Things You are Doing and Not Doing that Undermine Your Starting Commitment</h4>
        </html>

        <quizz name="doing-not-doing-thorough" type="yes-maybenot-understand">
            <question>Is your list of "doing/not doing insteads" robust and thorough enough?</question>
            <tip reject="maybenot">Did you list everything you can think of?  Did you give yourself lots of time to think?  Often we find that when we look at this column again, we can identify behaviors we didn't think of the first time. If your list is pretty short and/or rather vague, you might want to get the opinions of others who may have some insight about the things you do that stand in the way of reaching your goal. Think about asking your friends, your family, co-workers or boss, or anyone else who might be well informed about you and/or your Improvement Goal. If you have access to any expert advice (advice you might learn about from a well-regarded book on the subject or from someone you know who is skilled in the area you wish to improve), that will also be a good source to consider. What behaviors do they recommend?  What do they caution you not to do?  When you have added to your list, then continue on to see if those revisions in Column 2 help you revise columns 3 and 4.</tip>
            <tip reject="understand">Look at your list of behaviors in column 2 to see if there are other behaviors you should add. Is there someone who knows you well who can think of other behaviors to include in the list?  Have you heard or read any expert advice about your Improvement Goal that can give you more ideas about what to add?</tip>
        </quizz>

        <quizz name="doing-not-doing-too-long" type="yes-maybe-understand">
            <question>Do you have a pretty long and/or wide-ranging list of "doing/not doing insteads"?</question>
            <tip reject="maybenot">If you have included lots of different behaviors, your map might lose its focus. Check and see if one or two of the behaviors on your list seem like they are the ones that are the biggest obstacles for you. If there are such behaviors that seem to get in your way the most, make note of them to make sure you are paying the most attention to them when you start to think about your fears. Then continue on to see if those revisions in Column 2 help you revise columns 3 and 4.</tip>
            <tip reject="understand">Do you have too many behaviors listed?  Decide which behaviors are the biggest problems for you and make sure to think about the fears or worries you have if you do the opposite of them.</tip>
        </quizz>

        <html>
            <h4>Suggestions for Column 3: Your Fears and Hidden, Competing Commitments</h4>
            
            <p>Column 3 is where you are most likely to get off-track. It may be the case that you misread one of the directions or suggestions. For example, you may identify fears and/or hidden competing commitments that have a kind of noble ring to them, such as, "I am committed to not being selfish."  Or "I worry that other important work won't get done well."  Or you may come up with something that feels true but also kind of weak and unsurprising, such as, "I am committed to enjoying my meals."  (Who isn't?)  If either of these problems is true for you, we suggest you go back over our directions for identifying your fears and hidden, competing commitments to see that helps you identify something more powerful. Here are some additional suggestions:</p>
        </html>

        <quizz name="worries-powerful" type="yes-maybenot-understand">
            <question>Have you identified fears and worries that feel very powerful?</question>
            <tip reject="maybenot">
                <html>
                    <p>Focus on the behaviors in column 2 that feel as if they are the biggest obstacles for you and imagine doing the opposite. Give yourself more time to think and to imagine, to see what comes up. You may have more than one fear for each behavior. If you identify a worry or fear that doesn't feel really strong, keep looking to see if there is another fear lurking nearby. You can also continue to probe a weak-feeling fear by asking yourself "What feels the worst about that for me?" That may lead you to a more powerful fear. For example, imagine I have the fear, "I will feel disappointed or let down," I can ask myself, what would feel the worst about that?  Maybe what feels the worst is, "I won't have been able to control how I feel. I will feel out of control."</p>
                    <p>Another strategy to try is to ask yourself the following question:  "How might doing the opposite of my column 2 behaviors damage the way I most like for others to see me (or the way I most like to see myself)?"  Or try this question: "How might doing the opposite of my column 2 behaviors lead me to see myself (or lead others to see me) in a way that I would hate?"</p>
                </html>
            </tip>
            <tip reject="understand">Are the fears and worries in column 3 small fears and worries, or are they big ones?  When you see them, do you feel uncomfortable?  If they are small or don't feel uncomfortable, see if there are other bigger fears that might also be there.</tip>
        </quizz>

        <quizz name="competing-commitments-powerful" type="yes-maybenot-understand">
            <question>Have you identified hidden, competing commitments that feel powerful?</question>
            <tip reject="maybenot">
                <html>
                    <p>When you translate your fears to hidden, competing commitments, make sure you preserve the sense of danger in your wording. Sometimes the power of the fear gets bleached out, and you may need to reword your commitment so that it captures that danger. If you fear that your mother will feel deeply hurt when you don't eat her lasagna, but your Hidden Commitment is to "show how much I love my mother," you've lost something in translation. How about, "I am committed to always being the 'good son' my mother expects me to be and to live my life on her terms"?  Or, "I am committed to preserving the peace in our family, at all costs?"</p>
                    <p>Our list of common fears and Hidden Commitments can also give you some ideas. TODO-LINK</p>
                </html>
            </tip>
            <tip reject="understand">Do your Hidden Commitments lead you to feel uncomfortable?  Do they include some danger?  If the Hidden Commitments are not as dangerous as your fears, try to change them a bit so that they do feel powerful.</tip>
        </quizz>

        <html>
            <h4>Suggestions for Column 4: Your Big Assumptions</h4>
            <p>It can be really hard for us to see what we have been assuming if we can't imagine that things could be any different than how we have been thinking about them.</p>
        </html>

        <quizz name="big-assumptions-identified" type="yes-maybenot-understand">
            <question>Did you identify the Big Assumptions that keep your whole immune system in place?</question>
            <tip reject="maybenot">
                <html>
                    <p>Big Assumptions often involve ideas about what we absolutely can't do or shouldn't do.</p>
                    <ul>
                        <li>"I assume that if I try to lose weight, I will fail, and then I will feel worse than I do now."</li>
                        <li>"I assume if I do eat more healthily, my husband won't like what I cook and will be annoyed with me.")</li>
                    </ul>
                    <p>Or they may involve what we feel we must do.</p>
                    <ul>
                        <li>"I assume that I always have to be the one who helps others reach their goals".</li>
                    </ul>
                    <p>Look at your map to see if there are any places you seem to be thinking along these lines and consider whether you might be making some Big Assumptions.</p>
                    <p>Big Assumptions can also lurk whenever we see things in stark terms. If there is something that feels very black-and-white, like it is either all one way or all another way, you may actually be overstating things in a way that suggests you are making a Big Assumption. For example, if my starting commitment is to "find the beautiful, slim me that I dream of," and one of my fears is that I will fail and "see that I will always be ugly and fat," I've only given myself two options:  a wonderful one and a horrible one. What are my assumptions?  Perhaps they are: "I assume that if I don't follow my diet perfectly, and I screw up even once, then I might as well give up and admit that I'll never succeed."  Or, "I assume that thin people are morally good and deserve to be happy and overweight people are morally bad and deserve to be unhappy."</p>
                </html>
            </tip>
            <tip reject="understand">Your Big Assumptions support your immune system. Sometimes it can be very hard to see what we are assuming because we can't imagine that there are other possibilities. When you look at your map, ask yourself questions like, "What do I believe I can't do&#x2026;?  What do I believe I must do&#x2026;?  Do I see things too simply, as though they are, either this or that?</tip>
        </quizz>

    </mentoring>
</vertical>
